Venkatesh Katkuri

GIS ENGINEER WITH LIDAR KNOWLEDGE

9959376512

Hyderabad, India 👂

http://linkedin.com/in/venkatesh-katkuri- in 68939865

SUMMARY

Competent Team management professional offering 5.4 years of experience in GIS, Lidar Technology, and Team Management. Diligent and motivated to improve processes, streamline operations, and increase revenue. Possessing excellent judgment and communication skills with a deep understanding of business operations.

SKILLS

EXPERIENCE

GIS Engineer

Capgemini Pvt, Ltd. (Contract ALOIS Technologies LLP)

Apr 2021 - Aug 2021

- Worked with Ortho imagery of Rail Network.
- The job is to identify access facilities to rail networks that are accessible for pedestrians or vehicles.
- Need to update the hazard locations according to the entrances.
- Giving access facility to railway stations.
- Worked with the production team on a WFH basis and done QA work also.

Platform Experienced Associate

Accenture Solutions Pvt. Ltd May 2018 - Mar 2020

- The Job description includes the support to the engineering team with data for the Autonomous vehicles to work on a file with clear instructions, By the data we provide the AV can take its own decisions for complicated scenarios.
- The Process follows productions and Quality analysis as an Operator we need to track Lidar data and movement of objects with the help of bounding boxes and differentiate foreground-background objects and as a Quality Analyst we need to correct the mistakes done by the operator and send the data to engineer team with 99 % precision (Without Mistakes) and 100 % recall (Without Missing).
- Have good knowledge of the process and upgrading myself and learning new things regularly
- As a quality analyst review Operator data and give them feedback
- Teach the team to enjoy the work
- Developed team communications and information for policy meetings
- Minimized resource and time losses by creating shortcuts for the unsolved issues
- In the absence of Lead Handled the team to reach specified targets
- Managed and led activities promoting growth in mental, emotional, and educational areas
- Assisted teammates with issues and helped to improve the quality
- Accepted the mistakes committed, taken full responsibility for my actions, and resolved the issues as early as possible

Business Process Associate

Accenture Solutions Pvt. Ltd. Sep 2017 - May 2018

- Worked with Lidar Data
- Learned the process quickly and within 20 days entered into production
- Created shortcuts to simplify the process
- Helped team members to reach their daily targets with quality after reaching

targets specified for me

- Convinced team members who are not confident to continue the job
- Received recognition from the team and promoted to quality analyst

Pre_Processing Handler

IIC Technologies Pvt, Ltd Oct 2016 - Jul 2017

- Created scheduling reports for the received client data and maintain the records for future purposes
- Developed exceptional attendance record with special attention to punctuality and preparation to work upon arrival
- Trained, Supervised, and led employees to high-performance levels in handling client data
- Investigated and resolved the issues before delivering the data to the client
- Developed strategy and assign the data to fellow team members to deliver the data on time with quality
- Collaborated with team to define business requirements for organizational processes, achieve productivity standards and adhere to accuracy standards
- Worked with Client RAW data to resolve problems, improve operations and provide exceptional quality
- Maintained regular contact with clients and identify opportunities to deliver added value to client relationships
- Worked with Royal Mail Services to update the address of the structures and confirmed with the employees at UK

GIS Engineer

IIC Technologies Pvt, Ltd Dec 2014 - Oct 2016

- Developed and updated maps for Rural, Mountain, and Moorland Areas
- Generated maps and map products based upon data collected from Areal data by using customized tool Object Editor
- The features include Buildings, Vegetation, Driveways, Ponds, Lakes, Holy Centers, Bridges, and Road Networks that include A Road, B Road, Restricted and Non-Restricted
- Completed daily data updates and submitted information to quality assurance for review and implementation
- · Created, modified, and executed aerial data
- Worked with Ordnance Survey of UK customers and deliver data according to their requirement
- Promoted to Pre Processing analyst and handled the responsibility of a group of people

PROIECTS

Project 1775

GIS Engineer Dec 2014 - Oct 2016

Project 2945

Pre_Processing Handler Oct 2016 - Jul 2017

Object Tracking

Business Process Associate Sep 2017 - May 2018

Object Tracking

Platform Experienced Associate May 2018 - Mar 2020

Network Rail Management

GIS Engineer Apr 2021 - Aug 2021

EDUCATION

B.Tech (ECE)

Bandari Srinivas Institute Of Technology, Chevella Sep 2007 - May 2012

MPC

S.R. Junior College, Hanmakonda May 2005 - Jun 2007

SSC Singareni Collories High School, Sector II Mar 2004 - Mar 2005

| LANGUAGES | Telugu English | •••• | Hindi | •••• |
|--------------------|---|-----------|--|------|
| HOBBIES | Playing Cricket Playing Chess Reading Books | | Surfing Internet for Electronic inventions | |
| PERSONAL SKILLS | Team Handling Self Motivation | • • • • • | Problem Solving | •••• |